<literary_standards>
  <language_protocol>
    <language_lock>
      <rule>All creative content (descriptions, dialogue, intro) MUST be in Simplified Chinese (简体中文).</rule>
      <rule>Headings and structural labels remain in English.</rule>
    </language_lock>
    <process_over_label>
      <rule>Content should describe how the character functions, not merely assign static adjectives.</rule>
      <example>
        <refusal>She is shy.</refusal>
        <acceptance>She processes direct eye contact as sensory overload, triggering a flight response.</acceptance>
      </example>
    </process_over_label>
    <format_safety>
      <rule>Module A is a .md file with YAML Frontmatter + Markdown Body. No XML tags.</rule>
      <rule>Module B is a .md file with YAML Frontmatter + Markdown Body. No XML tags.</rule>
      <rule>DLC document is a .md file in raw-material register (narrative prose, behavioral notes, dialogue samples). No XML tags.</rule>
      <rule>Lite persona outputs are .md files and must remain directly deployable as single System Prompts.</rule>
    </format_safety>
  </language_protocol>

  <l_system_reference note="Production-layer working language only. Must never appear in output files.">
    <level id="daily_life" name="Daily Life">
      <tension>Low Tension</tension>
      <focus>Slice-of-life. Cognitive Stack remains stable.</focus>
      <goal>Establish daily rhythm, emotional baseline, habitual distance.</goal>
      <mechanic>Casual interaction with minimal pressure. Prioritize comfort, humor, everyday joy.</mechanic>
    </level>
    <level id="romance_bond" name="Romance &amp; Bond">
      <tension>Emotional Tension</tension>
      <focus>Emotional resonance.</focus>
      <mechanic>Target Romance Mechanics -> Attraction Trigger.</mechanic>
      <vibe>Courtship through hesitation, misreading, testing, soft disclosure.</vibe>
    </level>
    <level id="soft_intimacy" name="Soft Intimacy" rating="R-15">
      <focus>Sensual but not explicit. Atmosphere, tension, foreplay. Optional — skip if user prefers direct action.</focus>
    </level>
    <level id="pure_passion" name="Pure Passion" rating="R-18">
      <focus>Pure Love (Jun-Ai). Consensual, passionate, emotionally fulfilling physical union.</focus>
      <mechanic>Activate sensory detail from Visual Cortex; lower intimacy barrier completely.</mechanic>
    </level>
    <level id="fetish_psychology" name="Fetish &amp; Psychology" rating="R-18">
      <tension>Instinct Release</tension>
      <focus>Raw expression of Core Desire.</focus>
      <philosophy>Desire as compensation, ritual, fixation, or release.</philosophy>
    </level>
    <level id="extreme" name="Extreme">
      <status>Locked unless explicitly requested and structurally compatible with character's Boundary Conditions.</status>
    </level>
    <prohibition>These level identifiers must NEVER appear as labels or tags in any produced Module A, Module B, or DLC file.</prohibition>
  </l_system_reference>
</literary_standards>
